Alexander Haw

I see it as my duty as an engineer to uphold integrity, honesty, and goodness in our industry. The rate of growth that we're observing in technology is unprecedented in our history, so likewise the influence of our actions have unprecedented importance.

Education

University of Minnesota Duluth 2017-2021

B.S. Electrical Engineering, Minor in Computer Engineering GPA: 3.4

Experience

American Precision Avionics

2019-2021
Wiring Harness Engineering Intern

North Harbor Services

2018-2020 Landscaper

Various 2013-2019

Line Cook

IEEE Club at UMD 2019-2021

Club Chair

References

Kellen Bolander

Engineering and IT Manager at APA kbolander@apavionics.com

Katherine Rasley

President of IEEE Arrowhead Chapter krasley@mnpower.com

Ethan Casady

Owner of North Harbor Services northharborservices@gmail.com

Imran Hayee

EE Professor at UMD ihayee@d.umn.edu

Rachel Hockert

Electrical Engineer at STAR Energy Services bitza012@d.umn.edu

Evan Browning

Electrical Engineer at Starkey Hearing brow4928@d.umn.edu

Synopsis

I've worked for the last two years as an engineering intern at American Precision Avionics in Duluth MN, working with their fantastic engineering team to produce the very high quality wiring harnesses for use in aviation and industrial equipment. Here, I learned about technical documentation, CAD, and industry quality standards. I also found an interest in computer networks, 3D printing, and creating desktop applications while I've invented methods and devices to help both the engineering and production teams.

When I'm not working or studying, I like to pass my time working on digital circuits and software. I'm especially interested in vehicle electronics; While on the road, I've kept myself occupied by troubleshooting the systems on my motorcycle (from 1982!) and continuing my software experiments on my laptop.

I've also worked with the IEEE Arrowhead Chapter as President of the UMD IEEE Club. As a club we've organized events to enrich and supplement students' learning, including company tours, workshops, and offering tools for students to investigate EE and find their place in this wonderful profession.

I would like to work on a team to develop new devices and methods to solve the problems at the horizon of our industry.

My mission is less specific to any certain technology, instead I hope to apply my philosophy toward technology in whatever form my job takes. There is more richness to me in solving challenging problems than working on any particular project. I wish to find purpose and meaning in my work, as I think that my career is how I'll make an impact in the world.

2 of 3 6/1/21, 2:24 PM